(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T14:20:23.803661",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is ok.
さくらみこ 1st Live 受注生産グッズ 1 応援セット
Sakura Miko 1st Live Made-to-Order Goods 1: Support Set
さくらみこ 1st Live 受注生産グッズ 2
Sakura Miko 1st Live Made-to-Order Goods 2
さくらみこ 1st Live 受注生産グッズ 3
Sakura Miko 1st Live Made-to-Order Goods 3
さくらみこ 1st Live 受注生産グッズ 4
Sakura Miko 1st Live Made-to-Order Goods 4
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is ok.
むかしむかし 電脳世界から神様は
Once upon a time, from the cyber world, the gods...
生まれたばかりの世界を豊かにするため神の使いを創造しました。
To enrich the newly born world, I created a messenger of the gods.
名を さくらみこ
Her name is Sakura Miko.
神様のお使いはそっちのけでアイドルに出会いあこがれました
Neglecting her divine duties, she discovered idols and longed to be one.
でも さいしょは うまくいきませんでした
But at first, things didn't go well.
そこにみこを支えようと みこぴーが集まってきました
Then MikoP came together to support Miko.
それから たくさんの仲間に 出会い
From there, she met many friends,
努力し 頑張り続け
worked hard, kept doing her best,
そして みこは…
and Miko...
そんな私の夢は アイドルになることです
My dream is to become an idol.
やっほー！みこのソロライブ、みんな行くぞー！
Yahoo! Everyone, let's go to Miko's solo live!
ねえ 思い出したんだ ふっと涙した日を
Hey, I suddenly remembered the day I shed tears.
さあ 数えてみようか これまで描いた奇跡を
Now, let's count the miracles we've drawn so far.
一つ 止まらない足で 二つ 超えていく夢は
One, with unstopping feet, two, dreams we surpass,
三つ 繋がる絆は 君と広げてきたんだよ
three, the bonds connecting us that we spread out with you.
何度でも 咲き誇りに 続いてく物語は
No matter how many times, the story continuing to bloom proudly
まだ 見たことのない 景色を探しにいこう
let's go search for scenery we've never seen yet.
花びら 一つずつが 小さくてもほら 支え合えたら
Even if each petal is small, look, if we support each other,
桜になれるよ ぼくらが繋いだ
we can become cherry blossoms, connected by us.
大きな木は まだ これからも
The big tree, still, from now on too,
春風にのって 伸びてくのさ
riding on the spring breeze, will keep growing.
一つ 涙こぼれたら 二つ 両手をたたいて
One, if a tear falls, two, clapping both hands,
三つ 数えてはじめよう 君と入れた大事を
three, let's start counting the precious things we put in with you.
弱音と本音で泣いたり 諦めかけたルートも
Crying with weakness and true feelings, even the routes we almost gave up on...
振り返っては何度も 強く慣れたんだ
looking back over and over, we became strong.
枝ひとつずつじゃ 折れそうでもほら
Even if each branch alone seems ready to break, look,
支え合えたら 暖かい春になれるよ
if we support each other, we can become a warm spring.
枝たちはああ さぞ形は花びら その気持ち言葉すら超えて 届けるのさ
The branches—ah, their shapes are flower petals; surpassing even feelings and words, delivering them!
冴えない私は 好きになってくれたこと これからも誇りだって
The uninspired me, the fact that you came to love me, I'll proudly say it'll be my pride from now on too.
させない闇手でで 強がりを隠してた頃よりも 強く大きくなったでしょ
Stronger and bigger than when I hid my bravado in the unyielding darkness, right?
君は支えぬ代わりになりたいから
Because I want to be the one to support you in return,
空に願う星 涙を預けて 空々バックもいっぱい踏み込もう
Stars wished upon the sky, entrusting tears, let's step fully into the empty sky too.
ぼくらが育てた 大きな木は ほら こんなにも揺るがないような 場所にいるよ
The big tree we raised, look, is in a place that won't waver no matter what.
ラララララララ
La la la la...
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さあゆこう！！！
Let's go!!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場
Don't underestimate an elite's monopoly!
＼みこち！みこち！／
\Mikochi! Mikochi!/
配信だ！きょうも集まれーー！！！
It's a stream! Gather around today too—!!
箱庭で愛を！！！
Give me love in this miniature garden!
叫んで育て！このアホ毛！
Shout and grow! This ahoge!
わがった！→わかんない！の繰り返し
Got it! -> Don't get it! On repeat
だけど超越していくにゃえ！
Yet surpassing it all, nya-eh!
ポンな人生！！！
A clumsy life!!!
えりーと！舐めんな！
Elite! Don't underestimate me!
バチ当たるで
You'll get bad karma
あんだお！？やんのかおまえら！！
What's that!? You want a piece of this?!
飛んでみろオイ！
Try and fly, hey!
＼みこ…！俺、恥ずかしいよ！／
\Miko...! I'm so embarrassed!/
でまれっ！！
Get out!!
叩き直したるにゃえ！
I'll beat you back into shape!
そんな根性！
Such guts!
＼みこ…！俺、恥ずかしいよ！／
\Miko...! I'm so embarrassed!/
いまにみてなって
You'll see soon enough
そのうちマスターなオベーションよ
Before long, a master's ovation
あー ポンコツも
Ah, even a clutz
やがて羽ばたく butterfly！！！
Will eventually spread its wings, butterfly!!!
まいきち語録生み出したら！
Once Mikichi's vocabulary is born!
百人が無限色だーー！！！
A hundred people become infinite colors---!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さーゆこう！
Let's go!
全35p！声上げろ〜！
All 35p! Raise your voices~!
きみにはきみの！乳酸菌なんで！！！
For you, your own lactic acid bacteria!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さーゆこう！！！
Let's go!!!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場
Don't underestimate an elite's monopoly!
配信だ！きょうも集まれーー！！！
It's a stream! Gather around today too—!!
箱庭を燃やそう！！！
Let's burn this miniature garden!
真顔で使え！日用雑貨！
Use everyday goods with a straight face!
思い出詰まったロケットは水がなくても飛べるから！！！
A rocket packed with memories can fly even without water!!!
光ってほら！虹色だにゃえ
Look, it shines in rainbow colors, nya-eh
ひとりずつ名前呼ぶよ
I'll call out your names one by one
あえんびえん世知辛いにあえ！
Aen bien, life is tough, nya-eh!
この治安じゃ追われみの身！
In this lawlessness, I'm a fugitive!
怨念全開ポンデミック！
Resentment full throttle, pandemick!
悩みこくった頭もポンにして
Make your troubled head go pon too
めげない！しょうげない！痛くないにゃえ
Don't give up! Don't be shocked! It doesn't hurt, nya-eh
あらんどよの中も
Even in this turbulent world
あきらめんな！
Don't give up!
心・筆が走らせるにゃえ！
Let heart and brush race forward, nya-eh!
うまみみ・ひだりかぜ！跳んでみろオイ！
Umamimi, left wind! Try and jump, hey!
＼みこ…！俺、誇らしいよ！／
\Miko...! I'm so proud of you!/
これが大人よ！ホルモンまき散らせ！
This is what an adult is! Scatter hormones!
てこい原理で人生もゾッコンでバッコダンにゃえ！！！
By lever principle, life is head-over-heels and booming, nya-eh!!!
玄人もやがて羽ばたく butterfly！！！
Even experts will eventually spread their wings, butterfly!!!
さあ言葉ごと生み出そう！
Now let's create right along with words!
いま人生まっさだなかーー！！！
Right in the middle of life right now---!!!
あしたもうたおう
Tomorrow we'll sing again
この場所
In this place
寂しい思いさせないよ
I won't let you feel lonely
みこと！35p！
Mikoto! 35p!
みんなでつくる独壇場なんて！！！
A monopoly we all create together!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さーゆこう！
Let's go!
ちっちさい身体！声上げろ〜！
Tiny body! Raise your voices~!
汗も滴るいい女なんいて！！！
What a fine woman with dripping sweat!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!!!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場
Don't underestimate an elite's monopoly!
配信だ！きょうも集まれーー！！！
It's a stream! Gather around today too—!!
箱庭で騒がそう！！！
Let's make some noise in this miniature garden!
笑って挑めメタルゲー！もっと遊べ！！！
Laugh and challenge the metal game! Play more!!!
画面越しだってハイタッチ目指せば何だってなれるから！！！
High-five even through the screen, because you can become anything if you aim for it!!!
光ってほら！虹色だにゃえ
Look, it shines in rainbow colors, nya-eh
いっしょに行こう
Let's go together
ひとりずつ名前呼ぶよ
I'll call out your names one by one
あえんびえん世知辛いにあえ！
Aen bien, life is tough, nya-eh!
この治安じゃ追われみの身！
In this lawlessness, I'm a fugitive!
怨念全開ポンデミック！
Resentment full throttle, pandemick!
悩みこくった頭もポンにして
Make your troubled head go pon too
めげない！しょげない！痛くないにゃえ
Don't give up! Don't be shocked! It doesn't hurt, nya-eh
あらんどよの中も
Even in this turbulent world
あきらめんな！
Don't give up!
心・筆が走らせるにゃえ！
Let heart and brush race forward, nya-eh!
うまみみ・ひだりかぜ！跳んでみろオイ！
Umamimi, left wind! Try and jump, hey!
＼みこ…！俺、誇らしいよ！／
\Miko...! I'm so proud of you!/
これが大人よ！ホルモンまき散らせ！
This is what an adult is! Scatter hormones!
てこい原理で人生もゾッコンでバッコダンにゃえ！！！
By lever principle, life is head-over-heels and booming, nya-eh!!!
玄人もやがて羽ばたく butterfly！！！
Even experts will eventually spread their wings, butterfly!!!
さあ言葉ごと生み出そう！
Now let's create right along with words!
いま人生まっさだなかーー！！！
Right in the middle of life right now---!!!
あしたもうたおう
Tomorrow we'll sing again
この場所
In this place
寂しい思いさせないよ
I won't let you feel lonely
みこと！35p！
Mikoto! 35p!
みんなでつくる独壇場なんて！！！
A monopoly we all create together!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！
Nya-Hello World!!!
さーゆこう！
Let's go!
ちっちさい身体！声上げろ〜！
Tiny body! Raise your voices~!
汗も滴るいい女なんて！！！
What a fine woman with dripping sweat!!!
にゃっはろーわーるど！！！さーゆこう！！！
Nya-Hello World!!! Let's go!!!
えりーと舐めんな！独壇場
Don't underestimate an elite's monopoly!
配信だ！きょうも集まれーー！！！
It's a stream! Gather around today too—!!
箱庭で騒がそう！！！
Let's make some noise in this miniature garden!
あいさつ行きますよー！
Here I go with the greetings!
にゃっはろー！
Nya-hello!
すごーい！
Amazing!
はい、ということでね！
Alright, and so!
みこぴー！みこと一緒に！ありがとーー！
Mikopii! Together with Miko! Thank you so much—!
いや、ちょっとみんなの声がすごすぎる。マジで、みんなの声がすごいぞー！
Man, everyone's voices are just too incredible. Seriously, everyone's voices are amazing!
はい、ということで、さくらみこファーストソロライブ「フラワーファンタジスタ」が始ままりましたーー！
Alright, and with that, Sakura Miko's first solo live, "Flower Fantasista", has officially begun—!
みんな！来てくれてありがとうーー！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming—!
最高の夏、見せてねー！
Show me the best summer ever!
見えてるよ！
Can you see me?
みんな見えてるよね？
Everyone can see me, right?
いや、つるしにいっぱいみこぴーがいます
There are so many Mikopi hanging everywhere!
はい、ということで、もう本当にね
Yeah, so... truly...
ついに来てしまったという、このホヨウ感
the feeling of finally having arrived here,
そして、もう、なんか言葉にできない感動
and emotions that words can't even express.
もう、それでだんだんだんだん口がパソパソになってきました
And because of that, my mouth is slowly getting all dry.
みんな、ありがとー！
Everyone, thank you!
ちょっと待って、泣かせないで
Hold on, don't make me cry.
まだ早い
It's still too early.
まだ早いじゃな
It's still too early for that!
でさ、でさ、泣いてるみこぴーいるよね
And yet, there are Mikopi crying out there, right?
泣いとるやな
You're crying, aren't you?
そりゃそうだ
Well, of course.
だって、こんなにエリートなみこが、こんなに素晴らしく咲き誇ってる
After all, an elite Miko like me is blooming so magnificently,
アリアキ、ありがとがゆ、決壊場所に！
leading to the ultimate breaking point of gratitude!
ということで、ということでってよく言っちゃうよ
So... I keep saying "so, so."
7thめ、ついに、ついにソロライブ開催が、ん、決定してない
Finally, the solo live... wait, hasn't been decided—
決定しなくて、えっと、開催したー！
without being decided, um, we're holding it!
みこぴーも一緒に、たくさん咲き誇って、最高の景色を見ましょう！
Mikopi, let's all bloom together and see the most amazing view!
みこのことを、見つけてくれた全部の人に
To everyone who found me out of all the people in the world,
今日はここで、みになりたいよって人にも、全部全部関わってくれた人
and everyone who wanted to be with me today, and everyone who supported me all this time—
みんなに、この最高のライブを、みんなで届けようね！
let's deliver this ultimate live together to everyone!
一緒に最高のライブ過ごそうね！
Let's spend the best live together!
えーそしてね、無料チロの店っていうのをやってます
Um, and also, we've been doing free trial streams
TikTokとか、YouTubeとか
on TikTok, YouTube, and platforms like that.
でも、もうすぐ終わっちゃうかも
Though it might end soon, who knows?
わかんないけどね、わかんないけどね
I don't really know, but yeah.
そのために、早めに買ってね！
So make sure to buy it early!
買えー！
Buy it!
みんな勝手にって言って、買って買って
Everyone's like "just buy it yourselves," so buy, buy it!
はい、そして、少しの感想はハッシュタグ、咲き誇るみこちょをつけて投稿してください
Right, and please post your brief impressions with the hashtag #SakihokoruMikocho!
それでは、みんな、次の曲行くぞー！
Now everyone, let's go to the next song!
にゃ、はろー！ふぉーでいず！
Nya! Hello! The beautiful days!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Take a good look at me!
please call 「Elite」！！
Please call "Elite"!
さあ、待ったはなしだ！始めちゃえ！
Now, no waiting! Let's get started!
今日も気合い引き締めてえや！で、挑戦だ
Tighten your resolve today too! Let's take on the challenge.
躊躇は厳禁、足踏みしてないで
Hesitation is strictly forbidden, don't just stand there,
一緒に「せーの！」で、もっと前にいこうね？
with a "Ready, go!" let's push further ahead, okay?
さあ、なんとかたっちゃえ！飛び込んで
Now, get up somehow! Dive right in,
なんたってジッとしたってもの人生は冒険だ
because no matter what, even if you stay still, life is an adventure!
こんがらがったらまたわかんないぞ
If you get all tangled up, who knows what'll happen?
道のりは困難だ！なんだんだ！
The road is tough! What is this, what is that!
上等だ！だんだんだんだん！
Bring it on! Step by step!
メソメソしちゃって
Sniffling and crying,
気持ちに「待った」しちゃって
putting a "hold" on your emotions,
あれ？一体全体どうしたんだ？
huh? What on earth is going on?
絶体絶命！？
A desperate crisis!?
君たちには笑顔が足りないね！
You guys are lacking smiles!
大大大大冒険に飛び出そうぜ！
Let's leap out into a grand, epic adventure!
良いじゃんね！
Isn't that great!
大大大大失敗も重ねて成長して
Accumulating massive failures and growing from them,
happyなfeel soで
with a happy feel-so,
君と笑い話にしよう
let's turn it into a funny story together.
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away all your massive problems too!
いつか大大大大円の素敵な結末へ
Toward a wonderful, perfectly rounded ending someday!
please me!! さあ、ついてきて？
Please me!! Come along with me, okay?
進め！前代未聞のnew world！
Press onward to an unprecedented new world!
ソロライブ楽しんでましゅ！
Enjoying my solo live!
なに感謝してます
Expressing my gratitude to everyone!
ナイスコメント、まーぜんぜん
Nice comments, not at all!
ウジウジして、心にロックして
Fretting and locking it inside your heart,
にゃー！hello !! the beautiful days !!
Meow! Hello!! The beautiful days!!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Feast your eyes on this!
please call 『 elite 』 !!
Please call "Elite"!!
さあ、待ってたはなしだ！
Now then, it's been waiting for!
始めちゃえ！
Let's begin!
今日も気ぃ引き締めてええや！って挑戦だ
Today, too, keeping our spirits high is a challenge!
躊躇は厳禁 足踏みしないで
Hesitation is strictly forbidden, don't tread in place.
一緒に「せぇの！」でもっと前に行こうね？
Shall we go further ahead together on "Ready, set!"?
さあ、なんとかんなっちゃえ！飛び込んで
Now, somehow it'll work out! Dive right in.
なんたってジッとしたって人生は冒険だ
After all, even if you stay still, life is an adventure.
困りこんだら
If you get troubled,
またわからないぞ
you still won't know.
道のりは困難だ！
The path is difficult!
なんなんだ！
What is this?!
上等だ！
Bring it on!
ダンダン ダン！
Dun-dun-dun!
メソメソしちゃって
Whining and moping,
気に「待った」しちゃって
putting feelings on "hold,"
あれ？一体全体どうしたんだ？
huh? What on earth happened?
絶体絶命！？
Dire straits!?
君たちには涙は似合わないね！
Tears don't suit you guys!
大大大大冒険に飛び出そうぜ！
Let's leap out into a huge adventure!
良いじゃんねぇ！
Ain't it great?!
大大大大失敗も重ねて成長してさ
Accumulating huge failures and growing,
happyな feel so で
with a happy feel-so,
君と笑い話にしよう
let's make it a laughing matter with you.
大大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away all the massive problems!
いつか大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Toward a wonderful grand finale someday.
please me !!
Please me!!
さあ、付いてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の new world !
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
あながち間違ってるま～た墓穴も掘ってる
Quite wrong, you're digging your own grave again~
勉強！勉強！
Study! Study!
（はいはいはい、知ってます。待って、なんか違ってる！）
(Yes, yes, yes, I know. Wait, something's different!)
ぶっちゃんけ 有識者の皆様に感謝してます！
Honestly, I'm grateful to all the experts!
nice comment 's 待ってんぜ
Waiting for nice comments!
（あ～ね）
(Ah, right)
ウジウジしちゃって
Fretfully hesitating,
心にロックしちゃって
locking up your heart,
ほら、だんだんだんだんダウンしちゃって
see, gradually, gradually going down,
絶体絶命！？
Dire straits!?
君たちには笑顔が足りないね！
You guys lack smiles!
大大大大好きじゃ済まさないっ！
"I love you so, so, so much" won't cut it!
良いじゃんねぇ！
Ain't it great?!
大大大大満足のその上の感動を！
To emotions even beyond utmost satisfaction!
もっと欲しがっちゃって？
Crave even more?
豪快に贅沢に行こう
Let's go boldly and lavishly.
全然前進しないなんて凹んじゃったって
Even if you get depressed about making no progress at all,
ならば全身全霊エンジン全開
then with all your heart and soul, engines full throttle,
本気の全力で
with serious maximum effort!
nya ! hello ! ! さあ beautiful に！
Nya! Hello!! Now make it beautiful!
意気込んで進め！ freedom way !
Gear up and advance! Freedom way!
( wow wow )
(Wow wow)
乗り遅れんなよ皆！
Don't miss out, everyone!
( wow wow )
(Wow wow)
声を聞かせてくれ！ yeah !
Let me hear your voices! Yeah!
( wow wow )
(Wow wow)
歌おう声高らかに
Let's sing out loud and clear.
( wow wow )
(Wow wow)
ベイベベイベイベ
Baby, baby, baby...
なんていうか…
How should I put it...
ああ、なんだかちょっと言い表せない
Ah, somehow I can't quite put it into words,
一人ぼっちで見てた景色を
the scenery I used to watch all alone,
今はきっとあなたと冒険してる！
now I'm surely adventuring with you!
大大大大好きじゃ済まさないっ！
"I love you so, so, so much" won't cut it!
だから最大最高レベルにガチの全力で！
So with the maximum, highest-level serious effort!
nya ! hello ! ! 届いちゃうぜ！
Nya! Hello!! It'll reach you!
ずっと大冒険しようぜ yeah ! !
Let's keep having big adventures, yeah!!
大大大問題も吹き飛ばせ！
Blow away all the massive problems!
いつか大大大団円の素敵な結末へ
Toward a wonderful grand finale someday.
please me !!
Please me!!
さあ、付いてきて？
Come on, follow me?
進め！前代未聞の new world !
Advance! To an unprecedented new world!
刮目しちゃってくれ！
Feast your eyes on this!
please call 『 elite 』 !!
Please call "Elite"!!
キュンキュンみこきゅん
Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun
キュンキュンみこきゅんキュンキュン君にみこきゅん
Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun, Kyun-kyun Miko-kyun for you
これが全方位だよ
This is full-coverage!
みんなキュンキュンしてね
Everyone, be kyun-kyun!
行くよー！
Here we go!
猫耳みこちゃん
Cat-ear Miko-chan!
無料パートは終了いたしました
ご視聴ありがとうございました。
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.